Lena Gurr
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Printed Material, 1926-1978, Series 7:; (box 5; 21 folders)
  This series consists of clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs, and brochures.
  - Clippings, 1958-1978 (Box 5, Reel 4947)
  - Exhibition announcements and catalogs, 1926-1974, undated, (20 folders) (Box 5, Reel 4947)
  - Brochures, 1946-1948 (Box 5, Reel 4947)
- Photographs, 1912-1978, Series 8:; (boxes 5-7; 1.05 linear ft.)
  This series includes an photograph album picturing Gurr's mother, and Gurr at the Art Students League, with her friends, with Joseph Biel in their Paris studio, at the World's Fair, and camping with Louis and Adele Lozowick. Photographs of family members include Gurr's parents, her brother Abe, and miscellaneous nieces and nephews. There are also photographs of Gurr and Biel with friends including Herman Baron, Celia Bernstein [Gurr's sister], Hy Cohen, Minna Lieber Colvin, Al Greenberg, Louis Harkavy, Lily Leon, Abram Lerner, Louis and Adele Lozowick [photo by Biel], Maria Norman, Regina Phillips, Sam Popper, Anna Rosenblum, Miss Steinberg, and Hertha Wegener. Photographs of Gurr and friends in Provincetown include Mary Cecil Allen, the Garodnicks (cousins), Esther Goldberg, Muriel and James Kellstedt, Alfie Marx, and Eleanor Pelham Wickwire.
  The series also includes photographs of Gurr at her Brooklyn home; photographs of art-related events including colleagues Samuel Adler, David Atkins, Joseph Biel, Henry Botkin, Clara Fasano, Rita Gordon, Minna Harkavy, Gerritt Hondius, Joseph Kaplan, Jane and Edith Kogan, Lev Landau, Jacob Lawrence, Harold Le Roy, Irving Marantz, Vi Sigismund, Bernard Simon, Hilda Weingarten, and Sol Wilson; self-portrait photographs of Biel; and Biel's photographs of George Grosz.
  Biel's source material for artwork includes views of New York City such as miscellaneous street scenes, shanty towns and bread lines, activities at the waterfront, Times Square, clearing snow in Washington Square, activities at an amusement park and beach, one photograph of a John Reed Club gathering and photographs of miscellaneous unidentified individuals.
  The series concludes with photographs of art work by Gurr, Biel's photographs of his own paintings, and art work by Joe Jones and Louis Lozowick.
  - Photograph album, 1912-1939 (Box 5, Reel 4948)
  - Duplicates from photograph album (Box 5, Reel 4948)
  - Photographs of family members, 1952-1964, undated (Box 5, Reel 4948)
  - Photographs of Gurr by Joseph Biel, 1939, undated, (5 folders) (Box 5, Reel 4948)
  - Photographs of Gurr with Joseph Biel, photographed by Biel, undated, (2 folders) (Box 5, Reel 4948)
  - Photographs of Gurr by others, 1949-circa 1975 (Box 5, Reel 4948)
  - Photographs of Gurr giving painting demonstrations, 1949, undated (Box 5, Reel 4948)
  - Photographs of Gurr (and Biel) with friends, undated (Box 5, Reel 4948)
  - Photographs of Gurr and friends in Provincetown, 1956-1978 (Box 6 (hol), Reel 4948)
  - Photographs of Gurr (and Biel) at 71 Remsen Avenue, Brooklyn, 1940-1950 (Box 6 (hol), Reel 4948)
  - Self-portrait photographs of Joseph Biel, undated, (2 folders) (Box 6 (hol), Reel 4948)
  - Photographs of Biel's gravesite, 1944 (Box 6 (hol), Reel 4948)
  - Photographs of George Grosz by Joseph Biel, 1932 (Box 6 (hol), Reel 4948)
  - Photographs of art-related events, 1937-1977, (2 folders) (Box 6 (hol), Reel 4948)
  - Photographs by Joseph Biel of source material for art work, undated, (6 folders) (Box 6 (hol), Reel 4948)
  - Photograph album of sculpture by Lena Gurr executed at the Art Students League (Box 6 (hol), Reel 4948)
  - Photographs of paintings by Lena Gurr, undated, (15 folders) (Box 7 (hol), Reel 4948)
  - Photographs of prints by Lena Gurr, undated (Box 7 (hol), Reel 4948)
  - Photographs of sculpture by Lena Gurr, undated (Box 7 (hol), Reel 4948)
  - Photographs of paintings by Joseph Biel, undated, (4 folders) (Box 7 (hol), Reel 4948)
  - Photographs of works by others, undated (Box 7 (hol), Reel 4948)
  - Photographs of a painting by Lillian Cotton, undated (Box 7 (hol), Reel 4948)
  - Photographs by Joseph Biel of paintings by Joe Jones (Box 7 (hol), Reel 4948)
  - Photographs by Joseph Biel of lithographs by Louis Lozowick (Box 7 (hol), Reel 4948)